A Guide to the Papers of Howard W. Smith 1936-1969
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of Howard W. Smith 1936-1969
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
8731-a
This collection consists of ca. 3600 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This collection was a gift of Howard W. Smith, April 12, 1973
Scope and Content
The collection contains correspondence and other campaign material from House races with William E. Dodd, Jr., 1938, and Elizabeth Murray, 1944. Much of the material deals with Smith's actions on the House Rules committee, 1955-1966, and legislation which he favored or blocked, including the packing of the committee, statehood for Hawaii, the Library of Congress Madison memorial building, the National labor relations act, the Salem Church dam on the Rappahannock River, and the Alien registration act. The collection also includes a Verbatim record of the proceedings of the House committtee investigating labor board and Wagner Act. A sizeable portion centers around Smith's retirement in 1966.
Contents List
- Campaign, William E. Dodd, Jr. 1938 (Box 1)
- Campaign, Harold Ickes 1938 (Box 1)
- Campaign, A. Mollegen 1938-1944 (Box 1)
- Campaign, Elizabeth C. Murray 1944 (Box 1)
- Campaign expenditures investigation 1944 (Box 1)
- CIO political action committee 1944 (Box 1)
- Letters of Commendation, A-Z 1966, (6 folders) (Box 2)
- Letters of Commendation 1960, 1966, (2 bound volumes) (Box 3)
- Letters of Commendation 1966 (Box 3)
  Removed from printed booklet Presented to Judge Howard W. Smith with best wishes from his friends, Sept. 23, 1966.
- Papers and news clippings re letters of commendation 1966 (Box 3)
- Communism 1938-1939, 1966 (Box 3)
- Remarks in Congressional Record 1955-1966, (4 folders) (Box 4)
- Educational tv program interview 1966 (Box 4)
- Education and civil rights legislation 1964 (Box 4)
- President John F. Kennedy 1962 (Box 4)
- House Joint Resolution 280, Labor study committee 1945-1946 (Box 4)
- Library of Congress, Madison memorial building 1960-1962 (Box 4)
- Library of Congress, Madison memorial building 1960-1970 (Box 5)
- Miscellaneous 1940-1961 (Box 5)
- National Labor Relations Act 1940-1947 (Box 5)
- National Science Foundation bill 1950 (Box 5)
- Papers re The Negro revolution 1965 (Box 5)
  Speech by Smith.
- Newspaper clippings 1940-1941 (Box 6)
- Dean Ribble, legality of sending Federal troops to Arkansas 1957-1959 (Box 6)
- Rules Committee 1957-1959, (2 folders) (Box 6)
- Rules Committee minutes 1955-1956 (Box 6)
- Rules controversy 1961-1963, (2 folders) (Box 7)
- Salem Church dam project 1955-1957, (2 folders) (Box 7)
- Smith Act 1939-1969, (3 folders) (Box 8)
- Hawaii and Alaska statehood 1955-1959, (2 folders) (Box 9)
- Testimonial dinner 1966 (Box 9)
- Veterans Preference bill 1944 (Box 9)
- D.C.-Virginia boundary dispute 1938, 1945 (Box 9)
- Verbatim record of the proceedings of the House Committee investigating Labor Board and Wagner Act 1939 Dec.11-1940 Dec. 28, (4 volumes) (Box 9)